Finding Aid to the Education collection SSC.MS.00446
Sophia Smith Collection
- COUNTRIES AND REGIONS
  - United States: Individual states (Box 42)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 52)
      - Care and Training of Orphan and Fatherless Girls, Proceedings of a Conference on the Prospective Work of Carson College For Girls and Charles E. Ellis College, Philadelphia, 1915 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Commercial High School for Girls, Philadelphia, 1905 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Lincoln University, Oxford, 1866 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Little Red Schoolhouse by Helen Ives Lyon, 1962, and a letter from her son Robert L. Lyon, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Moravia Institute, 1851 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Moravian College for Women, Bethlehem, 1931 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Oakland Female Institute, Norristown, 1856 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Pennsylvania College for Women, Pittsburgh, 1931; 1933 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Pennsylvania Female College, Harrisburg, 1853 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Sharon Boarding School, Philadelphia, 1849 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Washington Female Seminary, 1882-83 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Virginia: Sweet Briar College, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 13)
- PHYSICAL EDUCATION
  - Clippings, 1896-1978 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets, 1880s-1970s; undated (Box 55, Folder 2-5)
  - International Congress on Physical Education, Smith College, 1954 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - International Association of Physical Education and Sports for Girls and Women, 1956-77 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - International Congress on Physical Education for Girls and Women (Box 55)
    - First, Copenhagen, 1949 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Second, Paris, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Fourth, Washington DC, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Joint Council on International Affairs in Health, Physical Education and Recreation, 1955-56 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - National Amateur Athletic Federation of America, Women?s Division, 1924-29 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Physical education and recreation in Kenya, reports by Barbara Dodds, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - National Association for Physical Education of College Women, 1951-63 (Box 55, Folder 14-15)
  - Title IX (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Constance Appleby, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - American Association of Health, Physical Education, and Recreation (AAHPER) (Box 55)
    - Annual reports, 1963-65 (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
    - Financial reports, 1963-64 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - 54th Annual Convention Proceedings and Third Year Book, Eastern District Association, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Division for Girls? and Women?s Sports, Executive Council: minutes, 1957-65 (Box 56, Folder 5-14)
    - Board of Directors and Representative Assembly: minutes (Box 56)
      - 1963 (Box 56, Folder 15-16)
      - 1964-65 (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Countries: United States, New York (Box 57)
    - Dobbs Ferry Finishing School: photo album of Margaretta Wood Oliver, 1897 (Box 58)
    - New York Collegiate Institute oversize materials (Box 59)
  - Women?s history posters, 1983-87; undated (Mapcase Flat file dwr 2)
  - U.S. (NY): Vassar Observatory photograph, 1872-74 (Mapcase Flat file dwr 2)
  - Biographical (Emma Willard) (Mapcase Flat file dwr 2)
    - Sheet music: "Rocked in the Cradle of the Deep,", undated (Mapcase Flat file dwr 2)
    - ?The Temple of Time,? poster and map, 1846 (Mapcase Flat file dwr 2)